Joe Hinkley

Web Developer

Seattle, Washington · 425.628.3155 · joe@joehinkley.com joehinkley.com · linkedin.com/joehinkley · github.com/joehink

PROFILE

I am a self motivated web developer with a strong work ethic and a passion for building web applications with a creatively simple design. I enjoy the collaborative process when I feel that my communication skills and technical skills improve the experiences of other people, so I dedicate my time to improve my flexibility and adaptability by growing my full-stack problem solving skill set. Whether it be for the front end or back end, I am always excited to put these skills to work.

SKILLS

Languages: ES6 JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Ruby, SQL **Frameworks:** Ruby on Rails, Express.is, AngularJs, Vue.is

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Technologies: React, RESTful APIs, SASS, Node.js, Redis, jQuery, AWS (S3, EC2, RDS), Git

EXPERIENCE

Web Development Fellow at General Assembly

Dec 2018 - Mar 2019

- 12-week full-time web development program conducted in an online setting.
- YouTube Search: Streamlined search application built with jQuery, CSS, and YouTube Data API.
- Color Saver: Multi-page web application for saving color palettes, Node, Express, and EJS.
- Routr: Angular application with Express backend that saves frequent destinations in MongoDB.
- Nursery: React app with Ruby on Rails API, for mothers who want to track their diet and nursing.
- Circuit Breaker: MERN stack application with Redux for creating, and timing circuit exercises.

Web Development Intern at Labs8

Mar 2018 - Jun 2018

- Collaborated with marketing team to redesign the Labs8 company website using WordPress.
- Given sole responsibility of prototyping and creating a web application that provided digital lunch menus for school cafeterias using Node, Express, and AWS.

Audio Engineering Intern at SkyMuse Studios / Clatter & Din

Jan 2017 - Oct 2017

- Introduced new mic placement strategies and techniques that were used in multiple recordings.
- Partnered with the head engineer to record and mix sound effects used in a short film.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Web Development Immersive	March 2019
Edmonds Community College Web Application Development	June 2018
Shoreline Community College Associates, Audio Engineering	June 2017